Ahmed Ali

Data Scientist

Graduate Data Scientist with 2 years of experience as a Data Engineer as well as a Software Engineer. I have a massive passion for applying state-of-the-art methods and models in the real world and impacting millions of customers. I am also an ambivert who loves going to the gym, playing video games, reading books, and taking part in group activities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

April 2022 – November 2022

Exporto, Germany

- Improved search experience for Exporto's customers by optimizing SQL queries (x2 speed) as well as enhancing the UX.
- Implemented a global category search from scratch to help Exporto's warehouse worker to process all the parcels efficiently.

Software Engineer Intern

September 2021 - March 2022

Amazon, Germany

- Implemented advanced filters for AWS QuickSetup services from scratch which increased customer engagement for AWS QuickSetup.
- Improved UX experience for QuickSetup to enhance user journey from landing the AWS website until creating their first service.
- Reduced the team's development time by 5% by Implementing a new workflow for AWS Synthetics so that the team can run it locally without deploying the code to gamma first.

Data Engineer

June 2018 - March 2020

EJADA, Saudi Arabia

- Implemented 10+ different data pipelines on Microsoft SSDT to transform and optimize data from SAP HANA to our Data warehouse (Oracle).
- Delivered 50+ ETL packages to production.
- Led a small team of 3 people to install a new environment for a data warehouse project.
- Segmented GAZT's employees by their progress using cluster analysis
 which helped the organization to measure the success of each group and
 dedicate some employees for specific tasks.

Software Engineer (Part-time)

May 2018 - July 2018

Upwork, Egypt

- Designed and implement React & Redux Application for a completed PHP scheduler project which was responsible for posting new articles/posts to specific social network applications in the scheduled time.
- Implement the full front-end part of a demo project using React and Redux.

CONTACT

- +49 1748908135
- AhmedOraby041@gmail.com
- LinkedIn
- Github
- · Portfolio

SKILLS

- Machine Learning
- Data Analysis
- Marketing Analytics
- Statistical Modelling
- · SQL Python Java
- Tensorflow
- A/B Testing

EDUCATION

RWTH Aachen
Master of Science
Major in Data Science
Minors in Mathematics – July 2023

Alexandria University
Bachelor of Science
Major in Computer Science
Minors in Mathematics – July 2018

OTHER

- Awarded the 3rd place at Meta hackathon 2020.
- Problem-Solver (Leetcode)
- Data Architect Nanodegree
- NLP Nanodegree